

Kennethcdlc@gmail.com

Sydney, NSW (0)





linkedin.com/in/kennethcdlc/ in







# SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a software engineer passionate on problem solving and constant learning. With years of experience in electrical engineering and hospitality, I get to transfer my critical thinking, problem solving and creativity skills into the everchanging field of software engineering.

# **PROFESSIONAL** SKILLS

Node.JS • HTML / CSS •

MongoDB • JavaScript •

Ruby on Rails • TypeScript •

> Firebase • React.JS •

PostgreSQL • Next.JS •

RESTful API • React Native •

> Netlify • Redux.JS •

Render • Ruby •

> Git • Bootstrap •

> > Material UI •

### **EDUCATION**

2022

**Software Engineering Immersive** 

**General Assembly** 

2018-2019

**Master of Project Management Graduate Certificate in Information** Technology

Central Queensland University

2010 - 2015 **Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering** 

**Bulacan State University** 

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Tooezy | Jan 2023 - Present

#### **Software Engineer**

- Implements full-stack development using Typescript, ReactJS, NextJS, React Native, Node.js, Parse Platform, and MongoDB.
- Develops and maintains responsive web applications, while also specializing in the design and optimization of cross-platform mobile applications.
- Implements server-side logic using Node.js and maintained databases for optimal performance.
- Manages relational and non-relational databases, ensuring data integrity and security.
  - Collaborates with dev team to establish continuous integration and deployment pipelines.

#### SUBI | July 2022 - Jan 2023

#### **Junior Software Engineer**

- Utilised Typescript, Node.js, React Native, Parse Platform and MongoDB in full stack mobile development.
- Designed, coded and debuged software product.
- Maintained and improved existing codebases.
- Worked with the business to implement new product features and functionality in a fast paced agile environment.

# General Assembly | 2022

#### **Software Engineer**

Participated in a rigorous 12-week, 480+ hour intensive program focused on comprehensive learning of essential full-stack software development concepts. The program concluded with milestone projects, where I applied the acquired fundamentals in practical applications.

- Project 3: Pokemon Quizzr | <u>Github</u> | <u>Live Site</u>
- Project 2: Expense Trackr | Github | Live Site
- Project 1: Manga-shoppu | Github | Live Site
- Project 0: Tic Tac Toe | Github | Live Site

#### Canva | 2019-2022

#### **Junior Chef**

Utilised Stakeholder management and communication skills to ensure a positive customer experience.

# **Dream Makers Construction | 2015-2017 Field Electrical Engineer**

- Managed costs and resources to meet construction budget.
- Designed revisions and additional works using AutoCAD.
- Identified labour and material cost revisions on electrical works.